MAYANK PATEL

Phone: 720.985.5463 E-mail: maxy.ermayank@gmail.com

Qualifications Summary

- 9+ years of software development experience including taking architecture challenges.
- Designed architecture, Developed and maintained Single Page Applications, Enterprise applications and Microservices using Agile life cycle.
- Strong knowledge and experience of OOP, SDLC and Architecture Fundamentals.
- Proficient with Mongo DB, Angular S, JSF, Java, J2EE, Spring and Play Framework.
- Good analytical capabilities and communication skills.
- Ability to quickly adapt to new environments and new technologies.
- Work well independently or in a team environment.
- Quality skill to train development team on several standard coding techniques as well as diverse technologies.
- Solid experience with front-end workflow automation tools like NPM, Bower, Jasmine, Protractor, Bower, Grunt and Gulp.

Skills

Operating Systems:	Windows 00/98/NT, Unix, Linux, OS X
Technologies:	ActiveMQ, Ajax, AngularJS, Ant, Maven, SBT, Play Framework, Java, J2EE, Spring, Hibernate, JUnit, JQuery, JSF, JMS, XML, JSON, HTML5, REST, CSS3, JMX, C, C++, Flex, ETL, Terracotta, Spring web-flow, Visual Basics, Gulp, Grunt, Swagger, Gradle, Protractor, Jasmine, Ionic Framework
Data Store:	Oracle, Postgres, MySql, Microsoft Access, Vertica, MongoDB
Source Control:	Github, SVN, CVS
Application Server:	Oracle (OC4J), Apache tomcat, Sun Application, Glassfish, Orion, Web logic
Tools:	Microsoft Office, Microsoft Project, Sun Office, Oracle Jdeveloper, Net Beans, Eclipse, Ultra Edit, Edit Plus, Sublime, SQL Manager, WinSCP, Putty, WinCVS, Macromedia Dream Weaver, Flex Builder, Web Sphere, Intellij Idea, Sun Java Wireless Toolkit, Robo Mongo, Mongo Hub, Apache JMeter, Xcode, VMware Fusion, App Dynamics, Jenkins, Artifactory, Docker, JScape MFT Server, Swagger, NGinx, SauceLab

Experience

Oildex, a service of Transzap, Inc. Denver CO (Jan 2016 - Present)

Application Architect (Jan 2012 – Dec 2015)

- Collaborated with management to successfully achieve project deliverables and schedules
- Supervised development team implementing variety of software development projects and data models.
- Analyzed, tested and promoted third-party resources across products and applications
- Acted as the primary mediator between enterprise architecture and application development teams
- Designed technical product strategies with detailed maps that simulated technological realities
- Took project requirements and developed architectural design documents
- Advised on solutions to improve existing architecture through advanced solutions
- Managed department's adherence to architectural governance standards and IT best practices
- Streamlined development with Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery using scaffolding, automation tools and Docker containers.

 Evaluated new technologies and ensured coordination among Data, ETL, Database and BI teams.

Oildex, a service of Transzap, Inc. Denver CO (Jan 2012 - Present) Senior Software Engineer (Jan 2012 - Dec 2015)

- Built new and migrated several SAAS based ePayable, eRevenue products using responsive, SPA (Single page Application) framework.
- Implemented REST services using Play Framework.
- Developed SPAs (Single Page Applications) using HTML5, AngularJS, Twitter Bootstrap and UnderscoreJS and REST services with play framework.
- Enhanced several caching mechanisms to Oildex architecture
- Implemented various parts of applications using Primefaces (JSF2) and spring web-flow.
- Trained Transzap software developer team to various levels to design and develop applications using JSF and spring web-flow.
- Performed migration for large part of secured Relational Oracle database schema of oildex platform to MongoDB. Also, implemented secured crypto based REST API using Apache CXF.
- Performed on several projects as architect and provided guidelines to different teams.
- Worked in team environment under agile development lifecycle and scrum model.
- Created Web based mobile application using JSF, spring framework and different parts of I2ee.
- Implemented Unit Tests and Integration Tests.
- Developed enterprise components for oildex platform using AngularIS directives.
- Responsible for providing guidelines to oildex software development team from architect point-of-view as needed.
- Presenting and defending design concepts to local and global stakeholders.
- Maintaining oildex theme.
- Created modern Responsive Dashboard for all oildex products using SSO (Single Sign-On).
- Performed vast migration from primary relational data store to non-relational data model effortlessly.

Software Engineer (Dec 2010 – Dec 2011)

- Created and improved various SAAS based products for ePayable, eRevenue in the oil and gas industry.
- Designed and Implemented ETL process using Java, J2ee, Hibernate and spring framework for Vertica data warehouse.
- Designed and developed vertica schema, projection and various administration functions.
- I was also involved in architecting the future of business intelligence framework at Transzap.
- I also migrated several back-end process like UNIX cron-tabs and daemon process to run in container using spring mvc framework.
- Refactored old legacy JDBC code to Hibernate and spring AOP transaction model.
- Implementation of REST services using Apache CXF.
- Maintained various parts of applications using ActiveMQ JMS broker and Terracotta caching.
- Worked in team environment under agile development lifecycle and scrum model.

I-engineering Software Pvt. Ltd. Gujarat, INDIA

Software Engineer (Dec 2007 – Dec 2009)

- Developed and maintained various Insurance Quoting Rater tools for quotation and policy management using Java, J2EE (JSP, Servlet), PrototypeJS, MySql, Postgress and Oracle.
- Worked with team to analyze, design, develop and test insurance quote tool for Home, Auto, Wedding Planner, Photographer, DJ and Contractor.

Zydus Cadila, Gujarat, INDIA

Software Intern (Jan 2007 – Jun 2007)

- Conducted research and performed data analysis, gaining a good perspective on software development methodologies
- Planned and designed Intranet Mail Server for the organization use.
- Assisted with Private network within an organization that conforms to the same standards as the Internet but is only for internal use within the organization, and was given increased responsibilities and recognition for a job well done.

Education

Colorado Technical University, Denver CO - 2011

MSM - Master of Science and Management in IT and Project Management

Sankalchand Patel College of Engineering, Visnagar, Gujarat, INDIA - 2007Bachelors of Computer Engineering

Government of INDIA (CDAC), Ahmedabad, Gujarat, INDIA - 2007

DJAVA

Interests: Photography